We have identified three major components
of a database: an entity and the records and
fields within an entity.
We now want to look at a key component of
entity design, a primary key.
Take a look at the data in this Person.Person
table.
See if you can spot which value is unique
in every record.
For one, the BusinessEntityID field looks
to have a unique value in each record.
In this table, the BusinessEntityID field
is a primary key field.
A primary key field is a field that ensures
that every record in a table is unique, which
is a key to solid database design.
Imagine for a moment that within this table,
you have two people with the same title, name,
and other information.
This situation does happen within a company
or customer list at times.
How then are we to discern one person from
the other?
The answer is a primary key field.
Let's make sure we have a primary key in this
table.
I will select and hold (or right-click) the
Person.Person table and select Design.
Doing this will allow other tables to use
this BusinessIdentityID on a person to get
the corresponding information.
Though this table already has a primary key,
if we wanted to set a different column as
a primary key, we could select and hold (or
right-click) the column and then choose Set
Primary Key.
That said, a primary key really needs to be
determined when an entity is first conceptualized
because a database designer should know right
away which column in a table will be used
to make sure every record in that table is
unique.